# ROMEO MARTINEZ

Contact romesmartinez@gmail.com 240.620.5942

I am a multidisciplinary designer, focused on product and brand design, based out of Maryland. Currently working as design lead at Employee Navigator. I'm a passionate designer with a mind for solving challenging problems and an eye for creating beautiful products, solutions and experiences.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Employee Navigator from May 2016 - Current PRODUCT DESIGN/LEAD DESIGN

As the one and only designer, I am responsible for leading the creation of prototypes on new & existing product features. I collaborate closely with developers, product managers, & QA to accomplish various product milestones. I am also in charge of running user testing & research with customers.

I am responsible for all brand & marketing (e-mail, blog, social media) materials, video & animation needs. I provided the art direction, and lead the production and execution of our annual "EN Users Conference".

O'keefe Communications from February 2016 - April 2016 FREELANCE VISUAL DESIGNER

Full Time contract freelancer, responsible for executing major conference keynote presentations and accompanying graphics. Responsible for producing, developing, and creating promotional video visuals and themes for client campaign use.

EventKloud From September 2014 - December 2015 UI UX DESIGNER & BRAND DESIGN

Serving as the lead designer in charge of managing company brand & Identity. Involved in the web design for EventKloud website, UX/UI design of their SaaS platform, mobile app designs and additional event site designs. Responsible for all company visual design(blog, web ad content, graphics, etc), and additional collateral for conferences/ expos.

GKA Advertising from November 2015 - December 2015 FREELANCE GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Rockville, MD. Working with the in-house design time at GKA and responsible for creating/editing promotional print material(brochures, flyers, catalogs), developing logo and branding identities, web graphics, and illustrating housing blueprint.

TrackMaven from June 2014 - September 2014 **DESIGN INTERN** 

Washington D.C. Responsible for blog graphics illustrations & visuals, speaker keynote presentations, web ad design, layout design & print design for expos.

U.S. Travel Association from December 2013 - May 2014 **GRAPHIC DESIGN** 

Washington D.C. Worked on branding & identity design for various internal departments. Also was responsible for publication layout, advertising/marketing design, and print design as well.

Earlier roles can be found on my linkedin

#### **EDUCATION**

BFA In Graphic Design The Art Institute of Washington Rosslyn, VA 2011 - 2013

Liberal Arts Associate Dearee Montgomery College Germantown, MD 2005 - 2008

#### **CERTIFICATES**

UX Design Certificate General Assembly Washington D.C. Winter 2017

**TOOLS** Sketch Invision Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Indesign Adobe After Effects Workfing Knowledge of HTML & CSS & Javascript Microsoft Visual Studios GitHub Powerpoint Keynote

## KNOWLEDGE

User Interface Design Human Centered Design Visualization of Userflows **Project Managment** Wireframing Pattern & Brand Standard Guides Web Usability Research on User Experience Good Sense for Typography Color Theory Knowledge